

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER IN TEST

QUALITY ASSURANCE (QA) | AUTOMATION & SOFTWARE ENGINEER | DATA ANALYST

Experience in automation, script creation, execution, and troubleshooting utilizing front-end automation tools and other disruptive technologies. Deploys specialist understanding of QA/testing principles and polices as a project leader for quality. Strong knowledge of data architectures, data flows, and process flow creation as related to enterprise information asset management and data quality frameworks. Effectively work in fast-paced environments with strict deadlines. Collaborative communicator who engages with cross-functional teams to specify testing strategy, build features, quality assurance, and strategic plan.

Core Competencies:

DevOps Practices • Scrum, Agile Methods • Data Management • Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC)
Web-Based Applications • Functional/System Testing • Integration & Service-Level Testing • End-to-End Testing
Test-Driven Development (TDD) • Behavior-Driven Development (BDD) • Customer Service • Fluent in English & Korean

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DEXCOM, San Diego, CA

Software Development Engineer in Test

2022 - Present

- Develop automation framework, test scripts using Python in Robot Framework and Selenium
- Automate the Application Programming Interface (API's) and integrate Pub/Sub and Google Datastore into automation test suite
- Implement Docker for test automation to run the Web UI Test cases and API Test cases and integrate into CI/CD.
- Design, develop, execute, and maintain Manual/Automation testing across different platform/domains to deliver high-quality products. Well-versed with different SDLC and proven ability to quickly identify and troubleshoot issues/problems/defects to be resolved.
- Involve in System, Functional, End-to-End, Regression, and Integration Testing
- · Perform analysis of defect Severity, defect tracking system, and defect Reporting
- Develop Test Strategies, Test Plans, Test Estimations, Test Cases- Execution, Defect Management, Scheduling and reporting on issues
- Demonstrate strong time management skills in handling multiple projects and deadlines under minimal supervision
- Create requirements traceability matrices which demonstrate test coverage of all features

SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS AMERICA (INTAC SOLUTIONS, INC.), Plano, TX Testing & Automation Specialist (Contractor)

2020 – 2022

Provide web-based manual, regression, and automation application testing as Lead Tester for Samsung Pay and 3rd-party app. Coordinate testing and automation activities of project team; execute technical tasks in the design, development, implementation, and documentation of data, automation, and controls tracking. Oversee lifecycle project experience through initial opportunity to requirements gathering, data analysis, data migration, and automation testing. Coordinate personnel and equipment; work with technical experts to ensure efficient problem resolution. Test contactless payment solutions including NFC and MST (Samsung Pay).

- Collaborated with team to create 40 partial test scripts in automation
- Leveraged advanced knowledge of Jira to create and implement visual dashboard and establish issue reporting function to improve bug tracking, developer communication, and team/headquarters (HQ) reporting capabilities
- Applied vast knowledge of technical engineering to understand customer needs, develop test cases, and design requirements

JIHOON KIM
Page | 2

- Identified required documentation and process for the project; led creation of design requirements
- Supported test data analysis and evaluated reports to determine if design met functional and performance specs
- Leveraged excellent communication skills to translate complex functional and technical requirements into comprehensive architecture and design plans understood across all levels.
- Saved ~93% in testing time with 90% accuracy (additional 10% required manual testing to maintain confidentiality of information, such as vendor one-time passwords (OTP), fingerprint registration, etc.)
- Increased user experience and satisfaction as a result of monthly testing for new Android package (APK) on Samsung Pay app prior to market release
- Participated on team that created 30 test scripts each in automation for regional carrier app
- Brought accuracy rate up to 96% and saved over 95% in testing time for regional carrier app automation
- Reported 430 bugs and issues within 2-year timeframe

GOODWILL INDUSTRIES, INC., Dallas, TX

2019

QA Engineer

Oversaw full project lifecycle for hardware testing. Defined scope, gathered requirements, led project kickoff meetings, and updated team on milestones to enable them to perform tests using mobile laptop model, confirmed usable hardware with automation tool, and assembled parts to create new hardware. Analyzed, debugged, and corrected bugs and enhancements. Managed all aspects of projects, including planning, resourcing, milestone tracking, commercial management, and customer satisfaction. Analyzed data and updated test cases based on uncovered defects. Designed test plans, scenarios, scripts, and procedures per business requirements and user feedback.

- Developed prototype test systems such as Hardware-in-the-Loop test suites and built automation software to interact with automated test equipment, units under test, and instrumentation
- Gained solid expertise in test equipment and measurement techniques
- Led design and creation of test racks and automated test equipment for production deployment
- Supported user acceptance testing (UAT) through data setup, access, and troubleshooting

NEWS KOREA TEXAS, INC., Dallas, TX

2018

WordPress Developer & Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Specialist

Developed landing pages, microsites, and complex/responsive website themes. Measured traffic strategies with analytics tools and monitored performance through uptime, hosting, and database analysis to ensure maximum capabilities. Supervised technical integration with 3rd-party services. Conducted QA on finished products to guarantee cross-browser, cross-platform, and multi-type device compatibility for web solutions.

Tools: HTML, WordPress, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, MySQL, Git, Google Analytics, Google Search Console

- Improved client's website ranking by 20% through development, implementation, and oversight of SEO strategies
- Increased requested website advertising by 30% by updating dynamics and interactive aspects of the website to ensure high traffic, page views, and enhanced user experience
- Augmented knowledge in development of custom post types, custom fields, plugins, and themes for high-traffic sites

EDUCATION

JIHOON KIM

MILITARY EXPERIENCE

REPUBLIC OF KOREA ARMY, Seoul, Korea

2013 - 2015

Information Researcher

- Seamlessly juggled multiple projects in challenging, high-pressure environments through prioritization and organization to achieve goals within strict deadlines
- Certified team advantage by utilizing analytical problem-solving skills and creative thinking in complex research environments

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Selenium Robot Framework/Web Driver • Keyword-driven • Python • Java • Postman• GitHub• Git

JIRA • Confluence • Docker • Bamboo • GCP • HTML • CSS • Android Package (APK)